export const english = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Write the opposite of 'prefer'.",
    Options: ["Like", "Hate", "Dislike", "Choose"],
    answer: "Dislike",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What is the opposite of 'bark cloth'?",
    Options: ["Smooth fabric", "Loud noise", "Silk", "By whom"],
    answer: "Smooth fabric",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "You bought all this food for me, but I don’t want. (Use: ….…needless………)",
    Options: [
      "why did you bring this food for me it is needless?",
      "You bought all this food for me, but I don’t need it.",
      "you bring me this needless food ",
      "This food you brought for me is needless ",
    ],
    answer: "You bought all this food for me, but I don’t need it.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "Write the correct sentence in brackets >The tyre_____________ as the driver was speeding. (burst).",
    Options: [
      "The tyre burst as the driver was speeding.",
      "The tyre was burst as the driver was speeding.",
      "The tyre bursting as the driver was speeding.",
      "The tyre has burst as the driver was speeding.",
    ],
    answer: "The tyre burst as the driver was speeding.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "A dictionary is_________________________ than an atlas. (cost).",
    Options: [
      "A dictionary is less expensive than an atlas.",
      "A dictionary costs the same as an atlas.",
      "A dictionary is more expensive than an atlas.",
      "A dictionary is not related to the cost of an atlas.",
    ],
    answer: "A dictionary is more expensive than an atlas.",
  },
];

export const sst = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "Name any one pack animal kept in people’s homes for the service it provides.",
    Options: ["Horse", "Dog", "Elephant", "Camel"],
    answer: "Camel",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Mention any one problem caused by floods.",
    Options: ["Drought", "Soil erosion", "Water conservation", "Crop growth"],
    answer: "Soil erosion",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "How are market places important to traders?",
    Options: [
      "They provide shelter",
      "They offer entertainment",
      "They facilitate trade",
      "They grow crops",
    ],
    answer: "They facilitate trade",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "Name the waterfalls located on the river Nile near Lake Albert.",
    Options: [
      "Victoria Falls",
      "Murchison Falls",
      "Niagara Falls",
      "Angel Falls",
    ],
    answer: "Murchison Falls",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Name any one island district in Uganda.",
    Options: ["Kampala", "Mbale", "Entebbe", "Ssese Islands"],
    answer: "Ssese Islands",
  },
];

export const science = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Give any use of proteins in the human body.",
    Options: [
      "Energy production",
      "Blood circulation",
      "Muscle building",
      "Bone formation",
    ],
    answer: "Muscle building",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "Give any way in which evaporation is important in the environment.",
    Options: [
      "Soil erosion",
      "Carbon dioxide absorption",
      "Earthquake prevention",
      "Cooling effect",
    ],
    answer: "Cooling effect",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Name any  human body organ protected by the rib cage.",
    Options: ["Heart", "Liver", "Kidney", "Stomach"],
    answer: "Heart",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "Why does sound travel fastest in solids compared to other states of matter?",
    Options: [
      "Solids have more air molecules",
      "Solids have high elasticity",
      "Solids have lower density",
      "Solids have a higher temperature",
    ],
    answer: "Solids have high elasticity",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      "State any way in which the spread of tuberculosis can be controlled.",
    Options: [
      "Mosquito control",
      "Handwashing",
      "Vaccination",
      "Dental hygiene",
    ],
    answer: "Vaccination",
  },
];

export const math = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Simplify: 9p + 7q – 4p + 3q.",
    Options: ["13pq", "13p + 10q", "5p + 10q", "9p + 7q + 3q - 4p"],
    answer: "5p + 10q",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Write 55,555 in words.",
    Options: [
      "Five hundred fifty-five thousand five hundred fifty-five",
      "Fifty-five thousand five hundred fifty five",
      "Five hundred fifty-five thousand five hundred five",
      "Fifty-five thousand five hundred fifty-five",
    ],
    answer: "Fifty-five thousand five hundred fifty-five",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Solve: 2x + 3x + 4 = 29.",
    Options: ["x = 6", "x = 7", "x = 5", "x = 8"],
    answer: "x = 5",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "Write CCXLIX as a Hindu-Arabic numeral.",
    Options: ["254", "249", "449", "359"],
    answer: "249",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Work out: 14 − 12 + 6.",
    Options: ["4", "6", "16", "8"],
    answer: "8",
  },
];
